arkive.org 2019-07-23

# Privacy Policy

At Wildscreen, we take your privacy very seriously and we promise to do our utmost to safeguard your personal information. This privacy policy describes how and why any personal information collected from you will be used, stored and processed by us and also outlines your rights and choices regarding your information. It applies to all activities and websites operated by Wildscreen.

**Who we are**

Wildscreen is a conservation charity based in Bristol, UK. Our goal is to convene the best photographers, filmmakers and creative professionals with the most committed conservationists to create compelling stories about the natural world; that inspire the wider public to experience it, feel part of it and protect it.

Wildscreen is a charitable company limited by guarantee and registered in England and Wales (registered charity number 299450 and company number 2206559), whose registered office is at 4A, 36 King Street, Bristol, BS1 4DZ, United Kingdom.

We also have a wholly owned subsidiary company of Wildscreen, called Wildscreen Trading Ltd, which carries out activities which may be advantageous and ancillary to the charitable objects of Wildscreen, and donates all profits to the charitable company. Our subsidiary may process personal information in accordance with Wildscreen’s instructions and policies.

The charity and trading subsidiary are different and separate entities. Within this policy, “we”, “us”, and “our”, mean both the charity and its subsidiary.

Wildscreen is registered as a data controller with the Information Commissioner’s Office under the Data Protection Act 1998 with the registration number Z2258589.

**What personal information do we collect and when?**

Personal information is data that can be used to identify you that you give us, for example by filling in a form, visiting our website or by corresponding with us by phone or e-mail. We may also receive your personal information indirectly via third parties such as social media platforms, or service providers acting on our behalf to deliver technical, payment, or analytics services. You should always check the privacy policies of services to which you provide your personal information to understand fully if and how it is shared with others.

Depending on the purpose for which it’s being collected, the personal information that you give us may include your:

• name  
• date of birth  
• contact details, including postal address, phone number, email address, social media identity  
• job title and employer name  
• gender  
• bank or credit card details  
• IP address and geolocation, and device used to access our websites  
• activities carried out on our websites  
• employment status, work history and unspent criminal convictions  
• next of kin details  
• UK taxpayer status  
• nationality and ethnicity  
• health/medical history

And any other personal information you provide to us.

We may collect personal information when you:

• contact us by telephone, email or social media  
• use our website(s)  
• purchase products and services from us, such as event tickets  
• make a donation  
• attend one of our events  
• create a user account for our website(s)  
• subscribe to receive email updates (requires your consent)  
• enter a prize draw or competition  
• fill out a survey or questionnaire  
• licence your photographs or videos to us  
• apply for a bursary  
• use our free wi-fi  
• supply personal details for a publicly accessible source, such as LinkedIn  
• agree to participate in an event or competition e.g. as a speaker or judge  
• ask for press materials  
• apply for a job or volunteering opportunity placement with us  
• become a supplier  
• become a sponsor  
• make a grant to us  
• otherwise provide us with your personal information through other means.

We may also need to collect and store **sensitive** personal information such as data about health, race, religious beliefs and sexuality.

We only collect this type of information where there is a clear reason for us to do so, such as if you are applying for a work/volunteering opportunity or in order to provide you with appropriate facilities or support. Wherever possible we will make it clear why we are collecting this type of information and what it will be used for.

**What do we do with your personal information?**

Depending on what personal information was collected and how, we may use your information to:

• further our charitable objectives  
• provide a service to you and/or fulfil a contractual obligation  
• process donations, purchases or other payments and verify financial transactions  
• process Gift Aid claims  
• manage our events  
• provide you with customer support  
• address any enquiries, concerns or complaints you have raised  
• deliver relevant advertising and marketing  
• measure and understand the effectiveness of advertising  
• provide information, at your request, about ways to support Wildscreen's activities  
• carry out research and analysis to better understand our users and improve our services and products  
• check on your marketing preferences from time to time to ensure they're up to date  
• create a profile about you to help us personalise our services to you  
• prevent or detect unlawful behaviour  
• conduct due diligence and ethical screening  
• safeguard our staff and volunteers  
• meet accessibility requirements, where specifically required and consent is provided  
• process your application for a job, volunteering opportunity or bursary  
• protect your vital interests  
• fulfil any obligations laid out in legislation

**Legal basis for processing**

Our legal basis for processing and storing personal information will depend on when and why you have provided us with your personal information. For example:

_For the performance of a contract or to take steps at your request to prepare for entry into a contract:_ If you set up a direct debit donation, or purchase a ticket to one of our events, we need to collect your personal information in order to fulfil your order.

_To comply with legal obligations:_ If you apply to be an event volunteer or work for us as a contractor, we will need to record and store your personal information in order to comply with various employment and tax legislation.

_Vital interests:_ If you're attending one of our events and there is an emergency or safeguarding issue, we have a legal basis to share your personal information with the emergency services in order to protect your health and life.

_Legitimate interests:_ We may need to conduct due diligence checks on potential and current supporters or funders to determine if they have been involved in fraud. By processing your personal information for this reason we are not harming your own rights and interests.

_Consent:_ If you have checked the appropriate consent tickbox or otherwise communicated your explicit consent, we may process your personal information for the purposes covered by the specific consent that you have given, such as sending you emails about our services, events and marketing.

Where we process sensitive personal information, we will make sure that we only do so in accordance with one of the additional lawful grounds for processing such as with your explicit consent.

**Keeping your data safe**

We take steps to ensure all your personal information is safe and secure, and that all staff are aware of and comply with their responsibilities in relation to the EU General Data Protection Regulation and the Data Protection Act 2018. For example:

• we have a formal data protection policy and procedures in place.  
• all staff undergo training in data protection requirements, with an annual review.  
• access to personal information is based on a 'need to know' basis and restricted to people who require it for legitimate purposes only.  
• we shred paper documents.  
• we have a formal retention schedule in place to ensure that we only keep personal information for an appropriate length of time.  
• we have security locks for our computers to prevent unauthorised access when unattended.  
• we enforce regular password changes through our IT systems.  
• we use industry standard security to encrypt your personal information when it is in transit to our servers. This includes firewalls, SSL encryption and PCI security compliance.  
• the servers that store personal information are in a secure environment in a locked facility.

**Sharing your data**

We will never disclose personal information to any third parties, without your explicit consent, other than for legal reasons or to data processors carrying out work on our behalf and working with us to provide a service. This can include email delivery, website hosting and analytics, payment processing and audience surveys.

These data processors are given access to the personal information needed to perform their functions but are restricted from using it for other purposes. We require them to comply with data protection regulations and we monitor them to ensure their compliance. Some of our partners have servers located outside the EU which means that when we collect and process your personal information via their service, your data is transmitted between the UK and a non-EU country. We will take steps to ensure your privacy continues to be protected in line with EU General Data Protection Regulation and the Data Protection Act 2018.

If our business is sold we will transfer your personal data to a third party: in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets (at all times in accordance with all applicable data protection laws); or if Wildscreen or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by Wildscreen about its clients (including those individuals who work for and on behalf of our clients) will be one of the assets transferred to the purchaser, in each case, the legal basis on which we process your data in these circumstances is our legitimate interest to ensure our business can be continued by a purchaser. If you object to our use of personal data in this way, the relevant seller or buyer of our business may not be able to provide services to you.

In certain circumstances we may also need to share your personal data if we are under a duty to disclose or share personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation.

**Your rights**

You have the following rights with regard to your personal information:

_Withdraw your consent at any time:_ You have the right to withdraw consent where you have previously given consent to the processing of your personal information, e.g. unsubscribing from marketing communications.

_Object to the processing of your personal data:_ You have the right to object to the processing of your personal information if we are doing so on a legal basis other than consent e.g. when we supply a purchase that you've made.

_Access your personal data:_ You have the right to access data we hold about you. We will need you to prove your identity before we release any personal information to you.

_Rectification or erasure of your personal data:_ You have the right to verify the accuracy of your data, ask for it to be updated or correct, and to request that we delete it (unless we have the legal right of obligation to retain it).

_Restrict the processing of your personal data:_ You have the right to restrict the use of your personal information if it is inaccurate, our use of your information is unlawful or if we no longer need to use the data for the purposes for which we hold it.

_Receive and transfer your personal data to another controller:_ you have the right to receive your information in a structured, electronic format, and to transmit that data to another data controller. This right applies where the personal information is processed by automated means and on the basis of your consent (such as marketing) or performance of a contract (such as a purchase).

_Lodge a complaint:_ You have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner's Office, although we ask to first be given the opportunity to resolve the issue.

**Protecting the privacy of children**

While some of our website content and events may be of interest to children and young people we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 16. If you're aged 16 or under, you must get your parent/guardian's permission before you use our websites or provide us with any personal information.

In the few instances where we knowingly collect personal information from children, we always seek parental consent and will only ever collect such information for the purposes specified when we collect it.

If you become aware that you or any child under your care has provided us with information without your consent, please send an email to [data@wildscreen.org](mailto:data@wildscreen.org).

**Use of photographs and video**

When a photographer commissioned by Wildscreen is present at any of our events, we may use the resulting images on our websites, social media platforms and in our publicity materials. Permission to use the images for promotional purposes is requested where the person is featured prominently in the image but not when they are in the background. If you have a valid reason why an image should not be used, please send an email to [data@wildscreen.org](mailto:data@wildscreen.org) to request its removal and we will endeavour to fulfil your request where possible.

**Why do we use cookies?**

When you interact with us through our websites or by reading our emails we and third parties may collect information by using cookies. We do this for three reasons:

_To provide you with the service you've asked for:_ For example, we set a cookie when you have logged into your web account on our websites so that the site remembers you and you don't have to repeatedly log back in every time you visit a new page.

_To analyse and improve your experience:_ We want to know what webpages and content are popular and what types of people are interested in them so that we can improve our sites.

_To provide you with adverts that are relevant to your interests:_ We use Google Adwords to promote our websites with adverts that shown alongside Google search results. You may be shown adverts tailored to you based on the pages you've viewed during previous visits to our websites.

You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject cookies and can control and/or delete them as you wish. Note that if you choose to reject cookies, your access to some website content and functionality may be restricted. For further information, see our Cookie Policy.

**For how long do we store your data?**

We will not retain your personal information for any longer than we need to use it in accordance with this policy. Unless we tell you otherwise (or you make a request for erasure), we will keep your personal information for as long as we have an active relationship, or you continue to want us to keep in touch with you.

Note that even if you request that we erase your data, we may still be required to keep it, or may keep it in a form that doesn't identify you, for the performance of a legal obligation such as financial records.

Once we no longer need to retain your personal information, it shall be deleted. Therefore, the rights to access, erasure, rectification and data portability cannot be enforced after the expiration of the retention period.

**Third party websites**

Our websites might contain links to websites belonging to third parties and we sometime choose to participate in social networking websites such as Twitter and Facebook. This privacy policy does not extend to these third party websites and we do not have any control over their privacy practices. It is your responsibility to make sure that, when leaving our websites, you have read and understood the other website's privacy notice.

**Changes to this privacy policy**

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 3 December 2018.

We may need to occasionally make changes to this privacy policy which you can view by checking this page from time to time for the latest version. If we make any significant changes in the way we treat your personal information we will make this clear on our websites or by contacting you directly.

If you do not agree to the new terms of this policy, you should stop using our websites, request to cancel any user accounts, and may also ask us to delete your information in accordance with your rights.

Do let us know if you have any questions or concerns by emailing [data@wildscreen.org](mailto:data@wildscreen.org).

**Contacting us**

To exercise your rights, make a Subject Access Request, or to send questions or comments, please contact us at [data@wildscreen.org](mailto:data@wildscreen.org) or write to us at Wildscreen, 4th Floor, 36 King Street, Bristol, BS1 4DZ, United Kingdom.
